today we're going to be talking about
genitive address our networks or how to
actually have them properly made
alright so generated other cyanate works
unsupervised learning generative models
so generating models again our models
that allow you to get something that is
in the input space most of the time
that's you know what is happening in
this field is that we assume there is
like a probability distribution over
these samples it doesn't have to for
example a decoder in a classical encoder
can be thought as a generative model in
my opinion and also for yan many will
disagree and they say generative model
has to have like an input which you know
follow a specific distribution we are in
the realm of unsupervised learning where
we don't have labels and so let's get
started with generative others are
networks
so what is this stuff
aha you should know all right so this is
the variation of the encoder the
variation of encoder is basically like a
normal thing coder where the encoder in
this case provides us the parameters for
a distribution from where we sample our
latent input to Zed okay so the only
difference between the normal one is the
again the sampler which is gonna kick a
random sample so instead of having one
simple code which is like one point you
have one input here you have one code
here instead now you're gonna have like
got some volume and therefore each like
point within this volume will be mapped
back to the original point yeah that's
you know a very important part about the
variation of the encoder so let's see
how these generally generative address
Arnette look like so we have this stuff
which is huh it's actually the same
right so what's going on here we have
the same generator in the same sampler
okay and then what is we have okay we
have another input there so the input
before it was on the left-hand side on
the bottom now the input is halfway
through and the output is actually also
halfway through finally we get that kind
of switch and then on top of that switch
we're gonna have a cost network usually
in the classical definition in the
classical formulation of a gun there we
have like a discriminator this commentar
needs discriminators are just plain
wrong option at least following young
suggestions which I agree with because
we see soon why we see that in a bit all
right now let's focus on the fact that
we have this cost Network okay so let's
we have basically similar models right
sampler on the right right hand side
this sampler on the left hand side we
have a decoder on the left hand side
which is basically generating something
but since the Zed is consider a code
we have a decoding step whereas on the
right hand side since Zed was not a code
but was simply an input then we have a
generator and that the said is simply
for example sample sample from Gaussian
distribution
wait you know normal distribution and
then that X hat will be generated by
this initially untrained Network the
cost network instead has to figure out
it has to be a high cost if we feed that
X hat the blue one because we want to
give like we want to say it is a bad
sample or instead if we sample the pink
one we if you get the the switch to
select the pink one we should have a low
cost because that would allow us to
figure out that we are actually doing
you know we are have actually a true
sample a good sample so summarizing the
sequence of operations we had at the
generator Maps my leighton input set
into this RN which is the space of the
input space so we have delayed and input
the orange one that is mapped into the
original input so we had that orange z
mapped or x hat in blue the top one
instead is a cost network in this case
which Maps the input which can be the
pink X or the blue hat the blue X hat
which is mapped to my cost so in this
case this cost it is a this cost module
is actually a it's a cost like in
Young's diagram is gonna be a square
okay which outputs a scalar this scalar
will be a high high value a large number
positive large number if the input is a
fake input and it should be a low number
probably up v-0 if we actually have the
input coming from the pink side the real
side okay and then how do we train the
system so the system will be trained
with different with different gradients
so the cost
network will be trained in order to have
low cost for inputs that are pink
in a high cost for input to dark blue
okay
so for example you can think about this
if you would have like you know a
discriminator in this case you may have
you may think about these as a
you know two classes classification
problem you try to get 0 for X pink pink
eggs and a 1 for the blue X we'll talk a
bit about why that's bad to use this 0 1
output in a second in a second but
otherwise we just want this network to
learn this cost okay so let's figure out
how this works in a diagram do you
remember how we were starting with a
variational encoder with a variational
encoder we were starting from the left
hand side right we were picking a input
and then we were so we were taking the
input we were moving to the latent space
we were moving this point because we are
adding some noise and then we were
getting back to the original point then
we were trying to get those points calls
together by using the reconstruction
laws and then we were trying to set some
structure in the latent space by using
that relative entropy term okay instead
for the gun the generative adversarial
Network we're going to be starting from
the right-hand side
so we pick a sample a random number
let's say 42 we feed that through a
generator and we get that blue X hat
over there then we're going to be
training in another network in order to
be coming up with a higher value for
that blue sample then we're gonna pick
another X let's say pink X in this case
on the bottom right of the spiral which
is gonna be enforced now to have a low
cost so this is pretty much like a first
initial big picture about how these
system works so let me try to give you
two more interpretation so this is like
the kind of definitions and this will
interpret like mathematical definition
and then the visual definition now
gonna be trying to give you a few
interpretations which I pretty like and
I can't make me sound like a fool but I
am a four so you know I just go for it
so you can think about the generator has
been a Italian and therefore I will be
using some proper Italian accent okay so
I'm a proper Italian now and I am in the
south of Italy and I'm gonna be trying
to make some fake man okay because we
are very good at using so we make a
second money and then we go to Germany
to get some to purchase something game
we go to Germany with this fake money
and then there is this different people
look at the US is like oh [ __ ]
Italian this is fake money and so we
can't really manage to we can really
manage to buy anything but since we are
Italian we have spice
we have spies in the okay there are
questions hold on maybe I'm offending
people now chart what's going on oh okay
you're enjoying the thing cool okay so I
was not offending anyone fantastic okay
so we have a spy back in Germany when
the spy is like calling back home hey
mom here you give us the wrong good
money like it was a so [ __ ] it up it was
just a you know not to prop better okay
okay so yeah chill chill down right we
are we are like back again home what
move is this that's just my own movie so
we are back in Italy you know we are we
are making you are able to make such
nice art and everything so we must be
able to make better money right so we
try now to fix the things that our spy
told us so we make a better money we go
back to Germany and try to buy other
things
and Germans are like uh-huh it's better
it's fake
okay then again you had a spy call him
back down to Italy and say Oh what are
you doing and they will understand
capisce you know and we are fixing it
the money no we are making several
iterations of that Thanks so we try to
make better and better versions of the
money finally we go back to Germany in
this case Germany because they have
money right that we had they have things
we can buy so we go back there and they
are like huh
it looks very good now I don't know how
to make in German accent I'm sorry
and so they accept the money right okay
and this is how pretty much these
generative other cyanide work works
we had like a generator which are the
Italian dudes in the south which are
making fake money and we are trying to
purchase something in Germany and
Germany is the discriminator and they
are very strict and very you know German
okay politically correct I'm not so
whatever but then we do have a spy right
and what is this spy
can anyone figure out what the spy
analogy here we haven't mentioned that
so far so the loss function back prop
discriminator okay some feedback okay
it's feedback and how is the feedback
coming from so whenever we train the
whenever we train the discriminator or
the coffee network right we have some
gradient that gradient allow me to do
two things right I can either in lower D
I can either lower the final value and
so I can tune my parameters of the cost
function let me go back to the cost
function so we have some gradients of
the final cost right so we had a final
some gradients of the final cost with
respect to the parameters of the network
and and so usually when usually when I
train the network the cost Network I
will try to tune the parameters such
that I will have a final lower loss
right this is a cost Network and there
is a loss on top of the cost Network
right it's a bit confusing so we're
going to be trying to optimize the
parameters of the cost network in order
to perform well and therefore having a
very low loss on the same way we can use
those ingredients that are computed with
respect to this network and you see my
mouse so I have you know my final loss
on top of here will come down with the
gradients and then you have here some
gradients in all these gradients you
know how if you change this X hat you're
gonna know how these final loss will
change right therefore you can train now
this generator with this gradient in
order to increase this final loss so
when we train this cost network we'd
like to minimize the final loss given
that we input these two different inputs
right but also we'd like to increase
this final loss so we'd like to make
this final Network perform worse by you
know improving the generator okay and so
these information that comes down here
and down this way which is the backward
pass right the input gradient will be
used for tuning the parameter of the
generator such that it managed to fool
the cost Network and so this is the
analogy with the spy in the German in
Germany is the distribution of Z fixed
so yeah so Z has it actually comes from
let's say a normal distribution I
actually don't really have anything
about anything to say about this
distribution as long as you pick your
distribution
you know the generator will map that
distribution into some X hat
distribution which will hopefully match
what is the pink distribution of the X's
okay so even even though Z the
distribution of Z is fixed we reach
be sure that we can change the generator
in such a way that we can minimize the
cost function right so although that
distribution is fixed the generator will
how do you say apply PL a why I think
you will apply this kind of distribution
such that you're going to be music
likely flowing into something that looks
alike the X in the pink X hopefully
okay I haven't told you about the
pitfalls of this system okay but
hopefully we'd like to manage to get a
distribution out of those blue X's X hat
such that they resemble the original and
distribution on the left hand side in
the pink one okay did I answer your
question yeah that makes it okay put on
the X produced by the generator be the
new improved money the blue one okay
yeah thank you I actually didn't finish
that one so the pink one are the true
euros we are using in Europe and the
blue the blue x hat are the money that
we make in Italy okay
Amamiya okay other questions I have a
generator was supposed to give negative
samples so negative samples okay so
there are two steps here
we provide negative samples that are
these X Hut's to the cost Network so the
cost network is trained in order to have
low values on the pink inputs and higher
values on the blue input okay and so if
the network the cost Network performs
well then the final loss here on top
will be very easier very low okay so if
the cost network is very is performing
very well then you're gonna have a final
low loss here nevertheless the generator
will be trained in order to increase
that loss because we'd like to fool
these Germans the Dozen
make sense could you just clarify what
the spy is in this analogy
yeah the Spy is the input gradient so
whenever here I have my cost network and
to train this cost Network I'm gonna
have a final layer here on top right
let's say this is an MSC for example let
me see with you know zero for whenever I
have an input eggs pink or some you know
value or let's say +10 in this case are
we try number for the moment value plus
10 for the blue guys right so my cost
network is a regression regression
network you can think about this as just
one single linear layer so it's like an
affine transformation of the input and
then these basically a final volume I
set it to be zero for the pink input I
have an MSc between the output of the
network and zero
for whenever I input the pink input and
instead let's say I choose an arbitrary
value of 10 to be a reflecting that the
input is the blue one right so we have
cost Network which is a network that is
outputting a single skat scalar value
and this scalar value will go inside the
MSC module here on top let me write
maybe so we can all see what's going on
so I have here my M and C this is my
loss function right so don't get
confused between loss and costs there
are two different things so I have my
MSC here and if I have this guy here my
target is going to be zero there's gonna
be my Y Y okay for this one and instead
if I input this guy here to the cost
Network I expect to have let's say in
this case an arbitrary plus ten so my
MSC in this case is gonna be you know
mean square error between the output of
the cost Network and zero in the other
case I'm gonna have the MSE between jobs
of the network and ten so the network if
I just train let's say we forget about
all this stuff right we have just a few
samples with weed with we think for the
moment that the generator is not
improving so we have several pink
samples and several blue samples and now
you train a network such that if I put
the input the pink one you're gonna get
a zero in the output and then if you put
the blue one instead you're gonna be
forcing the network to learn number ten
okay so you do some steps in gradient
descent in the parameter space such that
in one case you get zero the other case
you get then whenever you provide
several several samples right now that
we have this network this cost Network
you can think about having the cost
network to be actually the loss for the
generator okay and so if I have my
generator input-output in something and
this cost network will say oh it's a
very high cost then by trying to
minimize this cost you will try to
basically generate something that was
initially making that cost Network
providing you a low value okay is it
making sense you just quickly clarify
the difference between costs and loss
haha
the loss is what we use in order to
train something okay so my loss in this
case is the MSE loss this is my loss so
in order to train my cost network I will
have a loss function which is the MSE
loss function by minimizing the MSE loss
function I will be training the cost
Network
now the [ __ ] up part comes and I'm
gonna say that for my generator the loss
function that I want to minimize is the
cost Network so for this generator the
loss is the cost and I try to minimize
this guy output okay so this is also
relative to what Yun is teaching with
the energy based models you have energy
and we try to have low energies through
minimization of a loss function so the
loss function is what you use in order
to train the parameters of a network
okay so that's the difference so it's
the network okay so another additional
point is that a cost is like a
evaluation of some network performance
so if my generator outputs a bad X like
which is not pretty good-looking then
you're gonna have a high cost okay like
a high energy but in order to minimize
this energy usually you have to minimize
this losses okay so but again the
definition what we like to use is that
the loss is what you minimize in order
to train the parameters of a network so
instead like a cost can be thought as
you know I take an action and then I
have an action I have a cost for taking
that specific action okay so you take an
action which is like writing an email
about changing things and then the cost
is gonna be having every one piece at
you know makes sense right
you always learn something new okay
other questions so far
I'm sorry Alvin but I'm still be
confused about a constant generator so
for generator that generates the blue X
we want to increase the cost but you
just mentioned that we want to minimize
the cost is like the loss function for
the generator and we want to minimize
the loss so we want to increase the cost
or we want to decrease the cost for the
generator for the generator you want to
minimize the cost so we train the
generator through a minimization of the
cost Network value okay so there is two
parts of this thing let me change color
so first part is going to be the
training of this guy here and the
training of the cost network is made
through the minimization of the MSE on
top of here so this is the loss for the
cost Network so the cost the MSE here is
bit made between zero whenever I input a
pink input and then it's let's say for
this example like for sake of example I
like to have an MSc against 10 whenever
I input a blue sample okay so now we
perform several steps of gradient
descent in the parameter space of the
cost Network such that we minimize these
loss okay so now we have a network here
which is gonna be outputting 0 if I put
a pink input and input and output a 10
if I input a blue input so far are you
with me yes it was like cost will the
network cost will generate a high value
for blue X right yeah that's what we
train this cost to do okay so this cost
network will have to generate some large
value in this case 10 if I input a blue
guy and we'll have to generate a small 0
output if I put a 0 if I put a pink
input and in order to do that we do this
by minimization of MSE loss okay this is
first part sorry
you with me right yeah
okay fantastic now we have the second
part which is the cute version the
version that Yun likes that a different
version that you don't find online which
is the following so this cost network
now will give you values that are close
to zero whenever you input something
that looks like proper okay otherwise it
will put a high output let's say number
a value around 10 if you put inside
crappy input so now finally how do we
train this generator
well the generator now will be trained
through the minimization of the cost
Network right so the cost network will
say 10 here so this output blue guy here
it's bad guy right so if the generator
now switches slightly these acts to make
something that looks like this guy over
here then you get that from 10 we went
down to 0 right and therefore you got to
minimize this cost Network output value
and so we're using the cost network as
the loss for training the generator ok
what do you mean by like getting blue
axe closer to pink X right so right now
my generator outputs these blue blue X
okay and this is like some image that
looks bad or is a you know money that
really looks fake now how do you make
better money well the cost network is
gonna give you a scalar value for each
output your generator makes therefore
you can compute the partial derivative
you can look at the gradient you know of
that cost value I like to compute
partial derivative of these ok lower
case C so DC / d
eggs hot right so here I have the parcel
and this is our phone writing sorry
alright I can't drive okay ye no see
oh my god okay this was a lowercase C oh
it's like that alright cool so I come to
the partial derivative of my lowercase C
with respect to the X hat right so now I
have a gradient this gradient allows me
to move right around and I figure out
whether the cost is going increase or
decrease right so this is some kind of
maybe you know a little bit not standard
is in also yesterday Yan was talking
about this you know you have some inputs
in to your network you can decide to do
grid in the send in the input space I
can decide for example there is a
architecture which doesn't have a
generator at all you start with a sample
here and now you perform gradient
descent in this sample space and then
you move these samples such that you get
a lower lower value for the cost network
in this way you can you know get an
input that looks like resembling a good
input right the pink one does it make
that did I kind of explain myself or is
it still weird
there is much clearer thank you you sure
yeah yeah it's like taking gradients in
the interface and make it move towards
like and then decrease the cost so that
means the input actually gets better
like ass better money
right right right and then you can also
use this one is your gradient here
coming down here right and so now you
can compute with the chain rule also on
the partial derivative of this lowercase
C with respect to the parameters W or
the generator
okay so in this case then I can train
the generator I had the parcel of the
cost over the parameters and therefore I
can change now the values of the of the
parameters on the generator in order to
you know improve the network oh it
totally makes sense
of course yeah other train
simultaneously or train first the cost
Network order generator network right
people try both they say it's better
sometimes to keep one fixed while you
change in the other because otherwise
you have always a moving target then
there are contradictory evidence we are
actually gonna be really now some source
code after we cover the major pitfalls
but I'm gonna get back to your question
in a few minutes we don't need a
regularization like kld for saving gun
because we simple from normal yeah the
right directory direct yeah directly you
simple the orange guy here from normal
distribution so that's it right you have
a simple like a random number and then
you send this random number through the
generator that's it and my Google home
just came back to life
okay again sir your question I think
more questions then we have pitfalls and
then we actually gonna be looking at
source code yeah so it seems like we are
replacing that the reconstruction loss
with the differentiator Network oh how
does that help exactly why can't like
how is it bad to just use the
reconstruction loss Oh what is this is
this is this a very very good question I
mean I it's something I forgot
completely to say
so on the original encoder we were
always starting from some point then we
were getting back to this space we were
moving a little bit that point such that
we could cover some area and then go
back to the other side now you try to
make those two close right
but in our case right now in this janati
bothers our net we're actually starting
from the right-hand side so in the
general tea butter cyanide you start
from the right there is no whatsoever
connection between this guy here and
this guy here all you have is a cost
network which is telling you whether you
are on this kind of thing here right I
can't okay there's a cost networking is
gonna tell you in this case plus 10 here
and then it's gonna tell you let's say
zero here okay in the other case you
have a generative network here which is
mapping these input here down to here
right so one is trained in order to have
below values around the manifold and
then larger values outside and then use
some you would like something that is
like you know you may want some curve
levels right like that such that is you
move further away in the stuff keeps
increasing if you have a discriminator
they will force to have zero here and
one outside
exactly this manifold like very very
close by right and so that creates many
problems so okay let me try another
analogy and there is another analogy so
hold on there are questions more
question let me go with the analogy then
let's see whether this makes more sense
let me actually see myself such that I
can okay I can see now myself all right
so you have like some true data points
here okay and now you have some
generated data points over here that
have been generated by the generator
right so points here points down there
let's assume now we are talking about
this discriminator okay so that I can
illustrate what are the problems there
so you have a discriminator which
has these two kind of data you have true
data down here fake data over here and
so what does the discriminator do the
discriminator decision boundary is gonna
be just a line here right that is
cutting this stuff in half so far yeah
right yes okay good so now you turn the
on the second step second step is gonna
be you turn on gravity on this decision
boundary so this point that are here
will be both falling down okay the point
here get attracted by the decision
boundary so we train first the
discriminator we had this kind of
decision boundary then we train the gist
the generator you have these guys
collapsing down here so then you're
gonna be new situation you have through
data here fake data here you train again
the discriminator in this case you're
gonna have a decision boundary which is
gonna be half with here right then you
want you turn on gravity such that this
point here we've collapsed here right
and now you keep iterating this fry this
stuff will be getting closer and closer
and closer and closer to the true data
right so you had these points that are
like approaching and arriving to the
real data location so let's say now
you're using your discriminator you have
those binary cross-entropy
laws for training the discriminator what
is now the main issue let's say I do a
shifting I bring my true data here such
that we can see the data would think
happens so you have true data here
yeah generated data here right they are
overlapping and now you have a
discriminator cutting here so you're
gonna have overlap of these samples and
this discriminate or has no idea what to
do right so first of all you're gonna
get you know misclassifications just
because you thought you converge like we
actually converge right
if you if you think about that my true
data is here my generated data is here
they are over
shopping
so I actually managed to reach
convergence and now my discriminator has
no whatsoever clue how to split these
things apart so huh
so we don't converge or when we converge
we don't we we we get issues right huh
the discriminator I think this mater
just tells apart two classes
well this community cannot tell apart
the two classes because this input are
you know no more separated right they
are gonna be like if you actually manage
to get the generator to perform very
very good samples then these good
samples are you cannot tell them apart
from the actual real samples right you
know the discriminator has no whatsoever
clue about how to how to basically tell
them apart
so whenever the generator works the
discriminatory not work hmm how nice is
that okay
one other problem let's say again you
have the fake data here through data
over here and now you have a perfect
amazing awesome discriminator such that
here is absolutely zero and then here is
absolutely one okay so you have like a
basically like a step function you don't
have a sigmoid what's gonna be not the
gradient it's saturated right or it's
zero or it's one there is no more
gradient these points will never move
right so the the gravity that I was
showing you before that was attracting
these generated data through onto the
decision boundary was basically the
gradients that I saw the gradient of the
final of the output of the discriminator
or the cost network with respect to the
you know samples generated by the
generator but now if these discriminator
has a perfect is a perfect
discriminators zero here one here well
it's completely flat right if it's like
that there is no whatsoever
a gradient here right and therefore if
you're over here so let's say we have
data in 1 1 X right in 1 one dimension
you have 0 0 0 then you have 1 1 1 1 1
but then if there is just you know there
is no gradient this point will never
know they had to go in that direction do
we see oh we are bad guys we have a bad
value but then we don't know in which
direction to move because there is no
whatsoever direction the gradient is 0
it's a flat region right so this is a
very big issue right so whenever we
train this generator with the cellular
network you want to make sure that this
cost gradually increases as you move
away from your region of the true data
ok such that if there is a smooth or
it's like a you know a convex thing
right so if you keeps going up up up up
you always know which direction to fall
down in order to arrive at the location
where your true data is ok and my Google
home keeps rebooting I'm like tiny
little shipped off there you go is it
clear so far
yeah rip yeah one final issue was that
if we get a generator which gets every
point here mapped into this point over
here you know all the weights are 0 you
have the final bias be exactly this
value over here then that's finished
because the discriminator over the cost
function will say if done a very good
job and generators say yay
and then the generator just outputs one
image right this is called mode collapse
meaning that all points are mapped into
just one point and you can't do anything
about it so the actual full story is
that if every point here gets mapped to
this point here
then the discriminator will tell that oh
this is a fake point right and therefore
the generator will switch and will say
this is the real loud put right and now
you train the discriminator
discriminator say oh this is fake okay
so the generator we say this is the real
one right okay so you basically have a
network that is just jumping through the
samples and you can't fix that unless
you introduce some you know penalty for
not having some kind of diversity in the
output of the generator vanishing
gradients whenever you have like
saturated discriminators and we don't
like discriminators we prefer to learn
this kind of smooth laws the cost right
cost Network mod collapse that's things
like just describe right now we just
fold on one specific point unstable
convergence yeah and the point is that
whenever you get a very cute generator
the you know the discriminator will have
no idea what's going on you may have
like very big very big loss because you
may get you know these points would be
classified as this one instead is
completely classified as something else
you get some very very large gradient
the disk emitter will jump away and then
they generate this committee will jump
you know away and the decision boundary
will go in all bunkers bunkers and then
you're gonna have the generator trying
to run after the these you know running
away decision boundary okay and so there
is no convergence there is a equilibrium
so it's an unstable equilibrium point
which is very very tricky to catch yeah
so I understand we have some sort of
minimax problem here with a regenerator
and a cost but in general when you
optimize this I don't know if really any
straightforward ways to make sure you
convert you into the right point right I
am not sure how you figure out whether
you converge to a good point but through
visual inspection of your outputs of the
generator or you can train several you
can train several guns and then you
train a discriminator on
some image dataset and now you classify
you evaluate the quality of the of the
image right so this is like some kind of
not good metric we don't like but that's
what has been done is called inception
score so you train a network let's say
the inception Network that's why it's
called inception score on you know image
data set and then you can tray you can
try to see whether these generators are
giving you images that look like
something from you know from from this
training dataset again it's not really a
good metric but someone try to use this
for a way to evaluate generative to
evaluate and generative model before
starting before going to the notebooks
let's have a look to actually a
practical example of training laws for
these two networks we have just seen now
okay so the loss function for my cost
Network given the input X and the latent
input Zed in orange can be the following
so it can be equal my cost C given my
pink input X and then plus this part
here now which is the positive part of
enlarging M minus the cost I'm going to
give to a generated input which is is
outputted by my generator which is fed
with the input latent input a random
number okay
so G of Z gives me a fake input then C
will have to give me a cost and as long
as this cost will be lower than M this
part here will be positive part as soon
as C the cost Network gives me a cost
for this
generated input which is larger than M
then this part here and mine
some number larger than M is gonna be a
negative number then since I take the
positive part this goes to 0 so this
part of the loss goes to 0 whenever the
cost Network gives me a output that is
larger than M for a input that is being
provided by my generator on the other
side here we have simply the cost
associated to the correct ink input
right and so in order to squish this
down to zero you just have to have your
cost network outputting a zero whenever
the input is the good one ok so in the
example in the example was making before
I was saying that M is 10 and therefore
the network is encouraged to output a
scalar of 10 at least 10 at least and
right for inputs are coming from the
generator and said cause that is equal
to 0 is promoted by this term over here
so this is a example of possible loss we
can use for training the cost Network
known this is done in this paper here by
Jake icon and yon from 2016 then how do
we train the generator
well this white 3/4 because you simply
have the loss for training the generator
being equal the cost that the network
the cost network gives me for a given
generated sample right
and so my generator will simply try to
get a low cost and that's so pretty
all right ok again can we both can we be
more specific know what is this cost
network I have it's I haven't told you
yet a specific choice you can make for
creating a network that is giving you
this scalar based on the input but I
think you may already have some ideas
how this network can be made and so a
possible choice for for this network is
going to be in the following it's going
to be the
MSE the quadratic difference between the
decoding of the encoding of the specific
input so this is the reconstruction of a
out encoder - the input itself squared
right the norm squared so how does this
work well like if the out encoder is
being trained only on pink samples it
will be able to reconstruct pink samples
only right and therefore the distance
between my input the pink input and the
reconstruction of the out encoder when I
provide the pink input will be very
small hopefully right if we train this
nicely instead what happens now if I put
an input here that is far from anything
that is on the data manifold well my out
encoder has been trained to output
things that stays on the on the on the
on the data manifold and therefore there
will be a substantial difference between
my actual input and what my out encoder
can give you right the nice part of this
specific choice of course network is
that you can train these out encoder
without the generator right you can
simply train an autoencoder whatever you
can have like an under complete hidden
layer over complete and you use some
kind of regularization and information
restriction bottleneck but nevertheless
you can actually train this guy without
having a generator right and this one
you will simply learn what is the Train
the data manifold and now you can use
this as a proxy to establish the
difference the distance between your
current input and what the network
thinks the closest input on the training
manifold could be okay all right let's
move on in the last five minutes if
there are no questions we are going to
be reading the source code from Piper's
examples together and this I think it's
going to be the first case we are we
actually reading
programmer developer code I'm not a
programmer so whatever you'll be in
consuming so far where my notebooks
which were some kind of you know
pedagogical educational content which is
kind of massaged such that it looks nice
and pretty and has nice-looking output
right now you're gonna be reading
actually nice code written die by people
like that do this is their job right so
we go get up we don't go on PI towards
deep learning we are going to apply
torch my torch by torch examples some
pose ok so let's zoom a little bit ok so
here we have the DC gun and it's smooth
here okay so we can just go through this
code main things right so we start with
you know importing a bunch of crappy
things as usual you have an argument
parser such that you can send some
specific commands specific parameters in
the command line this printouts all the
options for the current setup this one
tries to make a directory otherwise you
know whatever this is if you choose a
manual seed then you're going to be
actually setting a manual seed in such a
way you're gonna have reproducible
results could a benchmark equal true
I think speed up the yes this one allows
you to have faster GPU routines
Karnas if you don't have CUDA you're
gonna be taking forever to train this
stuff data route whatever data set so
you're gonna be loading here imagenet
folders or l fw own data set so with
this is all things that we already know
ok so n GPU is gonna be the number of
GPU and there's gonna be the size of the
latent variable ngf and NDF
it's gonna be at T and G F and DF um the
number I think on the generative futures
and the number of discriminative
features and okay we have some specific
weight initialization which really helps
getting some proper training starting
and then let's actually have a look to
this generator right okay so this is
classical a classical and then subclass
generator you don't need these stuff if
you're using Python 3 so let's see so we
have a sequential right we have the
generator will be up sampling so such
that as you have seen from the last
homework you want to go from a small
dimension to a larger dimension you're
gonna use this model they have bench
norm reloj and so on right and transpose
convolution batch norm real low and keep
going and finally we have a tonnage we
have a tonnage because the output in
this case is going to be lying within
minus 1 to +1 forward is simply send
through forward through D you send the
input through the main and the main was
this one main main model right this is
for using data parallel if you want to
use several GPUs and then here is how
how do you initialize with the specific
initialization you define above so
simply just putting in short right what
does this thing do you input something
here that has NZ size right and NZ is
the size of the latent which is n Z&Z
100 so you input a vector of size of
size 100 so it's a tensor a one
dimensional tensor with 100 size the
size is 100 and so whenever you input
this 100 vector the output is going to
be something like a 64 by 64 times the
number of channels in case you have
color image or not right
nc and Symbian the number of channels of
the output the input imagery okay it
should be clear so far I know no crazy
things going on let's see the last part
and then like to see how the Train so
the discriminator is the same stuff you
have a sequential in this case we feed
these whatever number of channels times
64 times 64 and then you go down with
leaky read oh oh this is important so
leaky riilu in the discriminator make
sure you're not gonna be killing the
gradient if you are in the region in a
negative region right this is very
really important if you don't have
gradients here then you know you can't
train the diction the generator so you
keep the going down like that and then
finally they use a sigmoid because they
train this stuff is like a discriminator
like a classifier between two classes
and the forward is simply you send stuff
through the the main branch and they
initialize these network so we have a
net D and Natalie so the this
implementations slightly different from
the from what you were going over before
right because the discriminator is just
one it outputs like the sigmoid the only
difference is this line here right so
far so in the things we were talking in
the lecture just before we don't have
the sigmoid we just have this final
convolution later okay okay gotcha
of course second difference is that we
would not be using a binary cross
entropy loss this is the source of all
evils right BCE plus these sigmoid it's
wrong way of training a generative
address our network our generator okay
so nevertheless we go with the main
formulation here so let's see how it
works
fixed noise you just create a you know
some random stuff with a bad batch size
and the correct size here we have two
optimizers one optimizer for the
discriminator one optimizer for the
generator and let's see what are the
five steps that you should all know
right so let's figure out first of all
we zero the gradients of the
discriminator okay so now we have the
real data is going to be the data zero
that comes from the data loader right so
we have real data here and then we're
going to be having is
of labels which are going to be the real
labels okay so then we have the network
the discriminator is going to be fed
with the real input and then we have
some real output right and then you're
going to be computing the first part
which is going to be the criterion which
is the binary cross-entropy
between the output for whenever we put
the real input and the real label yeah
and then we perform the first step so
here we perform backward in this
criterion which is computing the partial
derivative of this binary cross-entropy
with respect to the weights of the
discriminator when we fed the real data
to the discriminator and we output we
try to match the labels which are the
real labels okay this first point number
one okay keep in mind second part second
part is gonna be you get noise and
therefore you get your network your
generator you feed some noise inside the
generator therefore you get some fake
output here I'm gonna be having my
labels now are filled with the fake
label okay therefore you feed this stuff
inside the discriminator we feed the
fake data but we detach right is the
important part so right now we fade
we've fed the fake data but we detach it
from the generator and then we train
again so we have the criterion we
compute the loss between the output of
the discriminator with the labels for
the fake class okay and then we perform
another step of backward so now we have
two backward right so we have backward
here and backward here and we have
computed the partial derivative of these
criterion in the case where we were
inputting real data and in the case
where we were inputting fake data so you
compute backward here backward here
there is no clear gradient right this is
the important part so we only called
clear the gradient at the beginning and
we compute first the gradient with the
real data and then
gradients for defected now you have that
we can compute this one right so we step
in the optimizer so we computed the back
part they did the partial derivatives we
computed the other parts of derivatives
now we stir finally we train the
generator and then we are done so how do
we train the generator now you fill the
labels with the real labels okay but you
still feed the discriminator and the
fake data the one that is generated by
my generator this discriminator should
say oh this is fake data but we say no
no this is real data and therefore you
basically swap the the thing right so
now you have the when we compute these
backpropagation we have this gradients
which are going in the opposite
direction these are trying to make your
network perform worse okay but then we
are going to be just stepping with the
generator right so this one computes the
partial derivative for everyone right
the first partial derivative of the
criterion with respect to the weights of
the discriminator and the weights of the
generator but then we are going to be
stepping only with the generator so the
generator will try to make lower
criterion and the criterion has the
label swapped right these are real label
for whenever we feed the discriminator
fake data and so this one is actually
working against the discriminator and
that was it so you had one backward here
you have another backward here and you
have another backward here and other
questions right now um wait what I was
looking to do the first two backwards
because they're both on the same oh yeah
right right okay so the first backward
here it's computed when the network the
discriminator the cost network has been
fed with the real data and the label
here our will feel our field with the
real label okay so this is the first
part of the backward so you have class
true class and then you have class
of the fake class right in this case a
week I generate my fake data through the
generator which was fed noise and then I
feed my discriminator with the fake data
but I stopped the gradient to go
backwards in the generator and this
criterion still tries to make the output
of the discriminator has been close to
the label and the label in this case are
the one the fake label the one that are
associated to the noise so more than
know it may emit maybe we can call this
noise level or maybe okay it's fake
labels finding fake is the data and then
the blue X Hut that is generated by my
generator network and then when I put
these X Hut here inside the sorry the
discriminator
I will tell the discriminator hey this
one should be labeled as fake labels
right and so you have this criterion
yeah
so in this backward you're going to be
getting those partial derivative of the
loss function with respect to the
parameters in the case when in the case
when we have fed the fake data and we
are trying to label them as fake you
know fake labels right we have faked
targets fake labels in the other part
here we actually were inputting inside
the discriminator real data and then we
tell the you know the network you have a
loss with print your output in the
labels which are supposed to be real
label so the first part you try to get
you get the partial derivatives
corresponding to the loss that has been
computed when real data was fed to the
discriminator in the second part is that
you have the loss of with respect you
know the loss of your output of the
network when we fed fake data right and
so here we simply do again another
backward so in this case this backward
this line here in this line here will
give you them they will accumulate right
because pythons by default will
accumulate every time you perform
backward so first part you accumulate
for the first half of the batch
and then second time you accumulated
basically you have the partial
derivative for the second part of the
bed the first part of the bed is the
real data second part of the batch is
the fake data overall you're gonna have
you know the partial derivatives of the
fake that the real data and the fake
data and then we use this gradient in
order to to tune to change the
parameters of the network the
discriminative ray does it make sense so
far yeah that makes sense but one of
them is increasing it another one so
this one so far are both trying to
decrease the criterion okay so this is
this is you can see here and this
criterion here has the output which is
fed of the discriminator when it was fed
with the real CPU data so you have real
data and real labels okay
so the criterion here is trying to match
to pay a real data and real labels
okay so far yes okay second part you try
to have the network here try to match
fake data with fake labor okay because
the output comes from this discriminator
which was input with fake data and then
this you know it should force the
network to say oh these are fake labels
right and so first one you had X
criterion here acting on true data with
true with labels that are sailing
telling you these are true data and then
you train you you have the the loss for
the network which is going to be sainted
this help instead should be labeled as
fake data right so this is still trying
to minimize these criteria therefore
whenever you perform the optimizer step
the optimizer step will try to lower
both this one and this one okay another
way to do this one would be to have the
summation between this one plus this one
you perform only one go in the same step
okay the alternative if you understand
what I said would be let me try to open
item eight this line here right so at
2:26
and then the other one was down to 235
right to 35 so we performed this one dot
backward and we did this on dock back
right but otherwise we could have done
226 plus the other one 235 and then we
just perform back backward here okay so
and this was an alternative which is
actually exactly the same as right now
if you perform twice backward on the two
different Criterion's is exactly as some
in the two Criterion's
and then performing backward only once
okay and then below whenever we train
the generator here we swap the the
labels right in this case we try to
train the we're going to be training d
so we step in with the generator
optimizer such that the we try to induce
the network
to output labels that are real labels
when we provide data that is fake data
right
so this stepping here it will not try to
untrain the discriminator but we will it
will train the generator such that it
tries to make up the discriminator
performing poorly so our generator is
generating our fake data don't we want
used a lot of parts don't we want to
take a step in the other direction for
that yeah so you want to take a step in
the other direction for the generator
right you said no for the fake data we
want to be able to tell it's fake yeah
and and that's that's that's where you
do that here if you have fake data when
you when you put fake data inside the
discriminator you also say in these
labels our fake levels right okay fake
label doesn't mean they are fake
the these are the label for the fake
data maybe this is weird so these are
the true label they are not fake label
their true label for the fake data okay
this I guess is seed that's what I does
dislike from other people writing code
that doesn't make sense in this case
before these for the generate for the
discriminator we try to lower this
criterion and we put this criterion so
these two lines are trying to match real
data the true datum with a true label I
in this case you have trying to match
the you know generated data with the
generated labels okay so both of these
two parts are trying to train the
discriminator such that it can tell
apart the two things so just to clarify
so for example like if returns produce
cat images then like the generator would
produce like oh I tried to make a cat
image here and here's label that saying
that it should be cat for since this
image I didn't try to make a cat so the
label is 0 for I didn't try to make it
yeah okay so let me go with cats I guess
it's gonna be easier or is it so here
we're gonna have real data
these are very nice cute pictures of
cats right and so we're gonna say
oh this output should be name is cut
right because it's very nice and looking
cute then I'm gonna be feeding some
garbage some noise to the generator this
looks like a monster okay ugly cut so
then we provide these monster looking
like images to the discriminator and
then we are going to be feeding these
laws with the you know verdict then
whatever the discriminator says and
wheedle able to say these are monsters
and so here you perform backward again
and then step such that you're going to
be training the discriminator such that
they can tell apart cuts from monsters
first part second part below we feed the
monsters in this case we still have we
have the gradients right in this case we
cut off the gradient pay attention to
this part here we cut off the gradient
so gradients don't go down the generator
in this case we actually input the fake
data
the monster looking images inside the
discriminator the discriminator say all
monsters monsters but in this case we
say no these are cute
cuts pictures and so now we train the we
perform backward which is computing the
partial derivatives with respect to
everything and then we step for the
generator such that the monsters that
the generator were was making now they
look more cute
I can be more cute than this sorry why
don't we send a gradient of the fake
data to the discriminator we do in the
second case right so let me answer the
thing so in this case here we when we
send when we send the gradients
backwards but back to the you know to
the generator we actually swap the
correct labels with the you know
incorrect labels in this case we input
monsters the decimator says these are
monsters and we say oh these are
good-looking cuts and then we train the
generator such that these monsters will
look like more nice-looking cut in this
case you don't want to send the
gradients through because in this case
you try to minimize the correct
classification part right so if you
would send gradients backward you would
basically get a worse performing
generator right because you don't want
to minimize this criterion you want to
maximize this criterion right so that's
why we don't have gradients in this
first case but we do have gradients in
this case because we absolutely want to
compute the gradients with respect to
the generator of this criterion it's the
combination VC lost and sigmoid because
I mean it's a problem because the
underflow so the problem with the dbca
thing here is the probability
probabilistic approach right so this
sigmoid if you train this network very
well this sigmoid will be giving you
zero gradients and because if you
saturate you know you're gonna have
you're in the two if you're not exactly
on the middle way if you are just away
from the decision boundary you're gonna
have basically or one it's so it's still
gonna have 0 gradient always going to be
the other side here still all 0 but
there is no gradient so if you're over
here you don't know where to go how to
go down the hill
right because there is no here is like a
clap oh so this is a first problem
second problem is that if you want to
really have a very vertical like a very
vertical edge here you will need very
very very very large weight okay
such that if you you know they have
larger the weight the larger is going to
be the final value inside the sigmoid
and if you want to get like a saturated
Sigma you're gonna have like pretty
large weight leading to that module and
this one creates um you know it's gonna
make your weights and everything kind of
explode and so that's why people want to
do several things like they want to
limit the norm of the weights then you
want to limit the norm of the gradients
and there are many many ways to patch
this architecture but that's dispatching
right we don't want patching we'd like
to know what is proper and what is
proper is gonna be basically and using a
out encoder for example for your final
cost network so if you consider the
reconstruction error of a note encoder
the reconstruction era of an auto
encoder will be zero of small if you
provide a data and it is coming from the
training distribution if you provide a
symbol it is away from the training
distribution to remember the manifold
from the last time then the auto encoder
will do a poor job at the reconstruction
and therefore the reconstruction error
will be larger right so instead of using
a discriminator you can use a out
encoder reconstruction error how can you
get more out of this course right
overall so let me give you a few
suggestions first comprehension if
something was still not clear just as
moving the question a section below the
video I will answer every question so
you will get it eventually
if you'd like to i get more news about
the field things i draw on in terms of
educational content and things I find
interesting you can follow up on Twitter
and there you have my handle I've seen
that you should like to have updates
about newer videos don't forget to
subscribe to the channel and activate
the notification bell if you actually
like this video don't forget to put a
thumbs up
it helps as well recommending this video
to other people if you'd like to search
the content of this lesson we have our
English transcription which is connected
directly to this video so every title in
the transcription is clickable if you
click on the title you get the right
director to the correct location on the
video in the same way each section of
the video is the same in title is in
transcription so you can go back and
forth maybe English is not your first
language but italiano habla espanol nous
oppidum comma speak Korean have no idea
how to speak Korean well we have several
translations of this material avaible
odd at the web site so and we are also
looking for more translations if you can
help as well it's really important that
you actually try to do some of the
exercises and you play around with the
notebooks and the source code we
provided in order to internalize and
understand better the concepts we
explained during the lessons contribute
this is really giving you the
opportunity to show your contribution
for example you find some typos in the
write-up so you find some bugs in the
notebooks you can fix those and you know
be part of this whole project by sending
me a request on github or letting me
know otherwise and that was it so see
you next time bye bye